hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is Jeremy
microkowski and this podcast I show
coaches trainers and mentors how to make
more money get more clients and scale
their businesses
to 100K 200k 300 000 and eventually
making millions of dollars in their
businesses like our clients have that
we've worked with now today is going to
be a great topic this is the first
podcast episode that I've made after get
my wife just gave birth to our son
um we just made sure that she was all
set up and she's got her family at the
house so I'm stepping out here just for
a few minutes to record this podcast
episode for you so here's something that
I wanted to kind of help you with
is a lot of you don't know
over the last four years we've been
running marketing for a number of
different companies Consulting while
I've been building this business and now
with the new baby here just our time is
a lot less it's a lot more valuable it's
a lot more scarce than before and so I'm
going to use
this episode is a perfect example for
you of what I've been talking about for
people truth is I don't have time to sit
down and map out the perfect podcast
I don't have time to make sure that what
I say lands perfectly with people
and truthfully if you are somebody who
does that and you're spending hours
mapping out planning out
you need to learn how to just get on the
surfboard
jump in the ocean
and ride the wave versus trying to be so
cautious and careful and and map things
out so much
that you end up wasting hours and hours
and hours of inaction
that you could be you utilizing to build
your business
you know right now I got a 20 minute
window where I know like my wife's good
for the next 20 minutes so I'm gonna
record this podcast episode right here
I didn't have an extra 10 minutes to go
map it out
and yet here I am talking to you about
something that I know
is going to help people
and so one of the biggest things that I
see after working with hundreds of
coaches over the years
is people
get so caught up in their head
overthinking about doing everything
right the right way making sure that it
lands making sure that it sticks and
they spend hours and hours spinning up
ideas in their head spinning around
potential scenarios of how things should
go without ever actually doing anything
without ever actually pressing record on
their course without ever actually
loading up chat GPT to write some copy
without ever actually starting a website
on Squarespace and building their
landing page and growing their email
list
and each one of these steps only takes
about 10 to 15 minutes on their own
but we end up
making them so much bigger
in our mind
than they really are
we end up making these ideas so much
bigger than they need to be and then we
come up with a thousand reasons why it's
not going to work out and needs to be
better it's not good enough and all this
and and this is the mindset that you
have to
learn to listen
it comes from a place of
your past it comes from a place of it's
the unknown you want to do things with
Excellence I get that
I get that that's me as well okay
but at the end of the day
this business can't be built that way
this business has to be built where you
more just open your mouth and speak
without thinking and move impulsively
and move when you've got a little moment
and you got a moment of inspiration
I hear so often from people like I got
inspiration for this offer I got
inspiration for an offer from MLS but
then I mean is it gonna work out is it
gonna is it gonna produce the result
that I want
and then for six to 12 months people
then talk themselves out of actually
doing the great idea that they had they
had this spark of inspiration
they had the spark of inspiration when
that spark comes in write it down
make a list
and then try to get that one item
knocked off your list in the next week
before going on to the next item before
going on to the next item
instead of
talking yourself out of it and wondering
is it a bad idea is it not going to work
out
and for those of you if if like you've
tried this
this is why again working on your mental
health has the greatest return on
investment in your business
mental health isn't a stigma
anymore
we've all had traumas we've all had
trials we've all had tribulations we've
all had things happen in our life that
have tried to convince us that we are
not good enough to do the very thing
that we were called that we were born to
do
I get it
we we're
growing and learning how to operate me
I'm growing and learning how operate as
a dad
even right now as I'm recording this
I know that there's going to be some
people that watch this and they're going
to judge me as a wicked evil father for
not being at my house with my wife right
now
that I am the scum of the Earth
because I'm recording this podcast right
now
stepped aside for five minutes even
though her mom and dad and sister are
there
and I've had to learn you know what I
can't worry what other people think
about me I can't let the perceptions of
other people who think that I'm the
worst human on planet Earth
and that they were appalled and
disgusted by my existence
to stop me
and I get messages from people I've
actually gotten messages this week
for posting content
on my social media but what a terrible
human being I am
great
let people think whatever they want of
you let people make up stories about you
let people imagine whatever they want
let people think whatever they want
about you it doesn't matter what you
need to learn though is to move more on
your impulses as a coach as a course
creator as a trainer as a mentor stop
second guessing yourself
stop second guessing your actions before
you do them
and just start doing them
so you're going to come up with all
these excuses all these reasons all
these things that play out in your head
as to why you can't
and so why right now is not the right
time as to why you need to wait until
another time to get started
and then that becomes your habit and
that becomes how you live your life and
how you exist for the next six to 12 to
24 months and and yet you say that you
want to do something and no progress has
happened
that's a choice that's you made on your
own
that's a choice that you made
to not take action and to let your brain
talk you out of doing the very thing
that you actually know
you probably should have done and I'm
not saying this to make you feel guilty
I'm not saying this to harp on anybody
we all got stuff going on
we all got life we all got experiences
we all got things going on inside of us
we all got things going on in our
families and with our friends and and
and and each of our situations are
unique
but you can still build your business
inside of
those unique situations
you can still create
the life you want
the more you learn to go with the flow
not second guess yourself not second
guess your actions not wait until
Perfection and just take imperfect
action jump into the deep end without
knowing if it's gonna work
jump into the deep end without having
the guarantee
jump out there without having the
certainty that it's going to go how you
want
and take the steps to create the life
and create the business that you've
always imagined this is one of the
number one things that stops people
as they second guess themselves they
talk themselves out of taking action in
their business and
this is actually one of the biggest
things that affects their time
management they say I don't have enough
time to build my business
no it's actually you've been talking
yourself out of using the time you have
and you have
not allowed yourself to prioritize
things in a way that allows you to use
the time that you have as best as
possible
and again it could be guilt shame
you know I'm going to be doing some
videos here with my baby strapped to me
maybe pushing a stroller around
things like that like
go with the flow of your life stop
trying to create this facade
this fairy tale version of your life
that you're trying to project to other
people that you think other people need
you to be
in order to be successful stop trying to
to create some false narrative that you
think that you're supposed to be in
order to be good enough
to put your business out there and just
launch already
just start
with what are those ideas that you have
what are those initial thoughts those
initial ideas
and and yeah
you're gonna probably end up talking
yourself out of doing it if that's been
your habit
most of your habits aren't going to
change overnight
most of your habits that have gotten you
to where you are today are not going to
change overnight
but you got to be intentional to say you
know what
I'm not going to let what I feel
what I think
what's going on in my brain
what I'm worried people are going to say
think and do
to stop me from creating the life that I
want when's the last time that you asked
yourself and answered the question what
do you want out of life
what's the life that you want to create
when's the last time that you answered
that question for yourself
some of you you haven't answered that
question in years because you felt
guilty because you felt selfish
because you've created this life where
you have to serve everybody and that
you're giving of yourself to everybody
else and sacrificing yourself and only
giving yourself the very little bit
because for some reason
you were taught
that you're not worth making yourself a
priority and I want to tell you this
today you are worth making yourself a
priority
you are worth
making yourself
important in your life
you are worth making your families
finances important in your life
you are worth prioritizing building a
business
in your life if that's what you want I'm
not saying you have to do that but if
you're listening to this podcast I would
I would think that you're somebody that
has a desire to do that otherwise you
wouldn't be listening to this right
this is like the
the one to two percent of people that
that want to be coaches that want to be
trainers that want to be mentors that
want to make multiple six figures and
change their family's future and change
their finances
that's up to you
the habits the beliefs
the the way that maybe you've been
living
the The Habit that you have of talking
yourself out of doing things and then
overthinking over processing and talking
yourself out of taking steps forward
talking yourself out of why it's not a
good time why you don't have enough time
but what you have to say is not good
enough and instead to start believing in
yourself start start declaring I have
value I have worth my time is valuable
and I'm doing my very best
and give yourself some self-compassion
give yourself some self-love
give yourself the grace that you give to
other people
instead of being so hard on yourself
I've been so hard on myself for so long
I've been so hard on myself for years
and I get it other people try to be hard
on us but we're our own worst critic
see I could either take those words that
people have told me about me being the
worst father in the world
by walking around my neighborhood for 13
minutes
and let that stew and destroy me
and I could let that get into my head
where people tell me
that that me doing this is the worst
possible thing that I could do for my
family that I'm harming my family by
making videos like this I get it there
are people that believe that
there are people that believe
that me making videos like this is
bringing harm to my family
it's okay let them
let them think whatever they want
let them believe whatever they want
let them judge you
let them criticize you
let other people rip into you
but don't give up
don't give up on your dreams don't give
up on your goals just because other
people tell you that you shouldn't be
doing the thing that you're doing just
because other people tell you that you
are a bad person for doing the things
that you know that you're called and
born to do you will have people
criticize you for that you will have
people come after you
you will have people try to stop you
from doing the things that you were born
to do
it's up to you to decide are you going
to submit to their Authority are you
going to let them knock you down beat
you up and rip you apart or are you
going to create the life that you want
that's what you get to decide for
yourself today
that's why I do these videos
because I want to inspire you because I
want you to take the steps
to move forward
and to build the life that you want
and to build the life that you know that
you were called to build for your
family's future
and to create
the type of
future that you know
you were born to live
and so that's why I'm making this
podcast episode that's why I'm doing
this
that's why I'm here right now
thank you
because I believe so much
in the future that I'm creating for my
family
I believe so much
in where I'm going
where I'm headed
what I'm doing that I'm not going to let
some Narrative of idiots on social media
dictate what I can and can't do
that I'm not going to let some Narrative
of people on the internet decide for me
what I'm allowed to do
I'm just not
and so
you got to decide to do that for
yourself and listen I know this this
might make some of you feel very
uncomfortable
what I'm saying right now
some of you may unfollow me
some of you may even report me
for this video
that's fine
it's absolutely fine
I'm not worried I'm not bothered at all
doesn't scare me
it doesn't scare me if I get canceled
for this
because I know that I know that I know
where I'm headed and I know that I know
that I know the dreams that are inside
of me
and there ain't nobody that's going to
stop them there is no situation that's
going to stop them there is no life
like
catastrophe that's going to make me give
up
too many of you have given up on your
dreams because life happened
too many of you have chosen
to not do
what you were born to do
because life happened
too many of you
are laying down
your future
the life that you want to create
because you want to make sure that you
do everything right and I get it that
comes from a good place you want to do
everything right but you're the one that
gets to decide what's right
you're the one that gets to decide
what the best things to do are
what's
the life that you're creating see it's
called you creating your life because
you're designing it not other people
other people aren't creating that life
for you
other people aren't
putting that life together for you
you're the one that's developing your
life
you're the one that's putting it
together
what do you want
have you ever answered that question for
yourself in a long time
what do you desire
if you could wave a magic wand what
would you wish could happen in your life
now let me ask you this why aren't you
doing it
why haven't you created it I got two
more minutes left
why haven't you built it
what excuse have you come up with with
for why you're not worth making yourself
a priority and why you've given up
the authority of your life to other
people
why you've given up
your life choices to the situations that
are going on in your life
why you've given up
on your dreams and the hopes that you
have because you'll
are afraid of things not working out
because you're afraid of things not
going your way it's time to choose to
stop doing that today
it's time to choose to create the life
you want that no matter who says you
can't have it that no matter who says
you're not allowed to that no matter who
says that you're wrong or bad or evil or
Wicked and that they're going to come
after you and stop you for creating the
life that you want that you still go
after it
and that's what I want to inspire you to
today
that's what my hope is with this podcast
that I inspire you to create
the life you've always dreamed of
that's why it's called the grow Your
Life podcast
I love you guys I love everybody who
listens to this
and I'm excited
for this next year
grow your life everybody
and we'll talk soon have a good one
[Music]